<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Stage Selector</name>
    <directory>stage selector</directory>
    <id>2787032335</id>
    <description>This mod integrates with Mod Config Menu to provide a stage selector for normal and greed mode. You can choose from all stages on the normal path as well as the pre-ascent and ascent.

You can choose between normal first floors and XL floors. There's no way to force XL ascent floors. The game will simply use whatever you had for that floor earlier in your run. Forcing XL happens via a callback so it's possible for other mods to break this functionality. Picking up Black Candle will disable XL floors.

There's options to:
[list]
    [*]Restart the game (with or without a specific seed)
    [*]Kick off a victory lap
    [*]Reseed the current stage (manually or automatically)
[/list]

You can use this mod to test or practice certain parts of the game.

You can tweak the following stats to help you play catchup if you skip to later parts of the game:
[list]
    [*]Speed
    [*]Tears
    [*]Damage
    [*]Range
    [*]Shot Speed
    [*]Luck
[/list]

There's options to give yourself:
[list]
    [*]The Polaroid: allows access to the Chest and the ascent
    [*]The Negative: allows access to the Dark Room and the ascent
    [*]Key Pieces 1 and 2: allows access to Mega Satan
    [*]Knife Piece 1: causes the mines escape sequence to spawn
    [*]Knife Piece 2: together with Knife Piece 1 allows access to the Mausoleum Heart and the Corpse
    [*]0 - The Fool: card that teleports you to the starting room
    [*]V - The Hierophant: card that drops 2 blue hearts
    [*]V - The Hierophant?: card that drops 2 bone hearts
    [*]VI - The Lovers: card that drops 2 red hearts
    [*]VIII - Justice: card that drops random heart/key/bomb/coin
    [*]Rune of Ansuz: rune that gives full mapping for the current floor
    [*]Cracked Key: single-use Red Key (creates red rooms)
[/list]

You can toggle the following debug option:
[list]
    [*]Infinite HP: taking damage won't hurt you (debug 3)
[/list]

There's 4 challenges included that you can use as a playground. All of them end after the first stage so you need to use the menu to go to the next stage if that's what you want to do. You'll start as Isaac with the D6.
[list]
    [*]Stage Selector (Normal)
    [*]Stage Selector (Hard)
    [*]Stage Selector (Greed)
    [*]Stage Selector (Greedier)
[/list]

This mod is enabled for other challenges too, but can likely break them.

There's an option to practice against individual bosses from each level. This works by moving you to the appropriate X-1 stage and using the goto command which takes you to a boss room that's off the map. Story bosses aren't included here since it's easy enough to trigger them by going to the appropriate level.

Debug console:
[list]
    [*]This mod adds 6 new console commands.
    [*]stage-selector
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector stage-name-as-seen-in-mcm
        [*]This can be used as an extension to the built-in stage command.
    [/list]
    [*]stage-selector-boss
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector-boss boss-name-as-seen-in-mcm
        [*]This can be used as an alternative to the built-in goto command.
        [*]This doesn't work in greed mode.
    [/list]
    [*]stage-selector-restart
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector-restart
        [*]This can be used as an extension to the built-in restart command.
        [*]It makes sure you always restart with a random seed rather than being locked into a seeded run.
    [/list]
    [*]stage-selector-seed
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector-seed seed
        [*]This can be used as an extension to the built-in seed command.
        [*]It supports more permissive seed formatting.
    [/list]
    [*]stage-selector-reseed
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector-reseed
        [*]This can be used as an extension to the built-in reseed command.
        [*]It does a few extra things like keeping XL state and resetting certain game state.
    [/list]
    [*]stage-selector-victory-lap
    [list]
        [*]Usage: stage-selector-victory-lap
        [*]Performs a victory lap.
        [*]Disabled in greed mode because it moves you out of greed mode.
    [/list]
[/list]

Examples:
[code]
stage-selector basement ii (ascent)
[/code]
[code]
stage-selector-boss mega fatty
[/code]
[code]
stage-selector-restart
[/code]
[code]
stage-selector-seed dhgr j6pc
[/code]
[code]
stage-selector-reseed
[/code]
[code]
stage-selector-victory-lap
[/code]

Most other things this mod does are already exposed in the debug console (giveitem, spawn, debug, etc). To change your stats, check out the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1889162991]Stat Change Commands[/url] mod or [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2666310447]Utility Commands[/url] mod.

Mod support:
[list]
    [*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2717876263]Alt path in Greed Mode[/url]: By default, the Repentance stages can be pretty sparse in Greed mode. This mod fills out these stages much better.
    [*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2835490368]Greed Alt Floors[/url]: An alternative to the mod listed above.
    [*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2813909722]The Cathedral in Greed Mode[/url]: Required if you want to visit the Cathedral in Greed mode (otherwise you'll fall back to Sheol).
    [*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2880387531]Revelations Ch. 2[/url]: Includes the Glacier and Tomb stages.
[/list]</description>
    <version>1.24</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Floors"/>
    <tag id="Bosses"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
